[Music]
w
good evening good day everybody and
welcome to the latest episode of the
asket show episode 180 I hope you're all
doing great and today I'm going to take
questions from uh the comments that you
have posted and I'm going to take those
so going forward every week I'm going to
have three live streams for the
foreseeable future one is going to be a
live chat live stream in which I take
questions from the live chat so that
everybody uh gets to participate and
then I'm going to have two live streams
in which I'm going to take questions
from the comments okay so let us see who
all is
there in the live stream I can see chag
ATI hello I do remember you Aman shast t
pamel nandi GK swapnil Joi red dakah
hero gusai
Bernal that Noob gamer Adit Singh dases
mahisha sh Karman Singh asor hello
Krishna raat a andit Singh om B hello
dios pitra
a Goku say G Jay guman Shan dakao d
adwit
anud Dan Rohan geopolitical du hello AG
mukad pran VI mul anit nen
lakshmikant meak Varma kavia Prav Mahi
Alo McLovin hello that Noob gamer I
think we spoke about that rishikes
simple 2222 Shri Hara
rudra
akiles py
SG uh Surendra Gupta and and and lots
and lots of other people Mato Peres
hello PR palab ABI shorts video Pam
gai and so on
okay uh with that done let us take some
questions and let's uh take let's see
what questions you all have asked let's
see Where Do We Begin let's begin here
by Jay Akash 06 who asks what are the
benefits of the Shahar Port deal with
Iran what are the benefits India will
reap okay so let's go straight to the
map because this is a map kind of thing
all right where's the map here's the map
so where is this port it is a port in
located in Iran all
right so we go
westwards and here we have the port of
chah Bahar over here this is the port
okay and if we were to use the SAT
images you'll find that this port has a
couple of terminals the port of Shahid
bashti and there's a different port here
as
well Daria kuchek chabahar Port Fishing
harble Harbor and so on so India has
signed an agreement with Iran which will
enable India to operate one of the
terminals in this port I think the
Shahid beesi for a decade 10 years
okay so that is what's come in the news
this happened this past
week so what are the benefits of this
for India I mean why I mean everybody is
talking about this why is this a big
deal well you to understand it's all
about geography historically India's
borders historical borders they touched
on Central Asia and Afghanistan
Afghanistan the past 500 years was no
longer part of India so India's borders
historically Afghanistan and Nations
like Tajikistan so that was the border
of India and India could access Central
Asia and
Eurasia from its borders from its
northern and western borders now after
1947 uh the so-called Indian leadership
of that time allowed the partitioning of
India and the creation of an extremely
hostile Nation called Pakistan a
temporary artificial nation and the
pakistanis have always had this policy
of denying India access to Central Asia
because now the entire access to Central
Asia is cut off by Pakistan and that's a
inherently hostile Nation as long as it
exists so India no longer has access to
Central Asia and and to Eurasia which is
a disaster which is something people in
India don't realize at all you just
don't understand geography because you
need access to Central Asia and to
Europe etc for trade purposes look at
China's OBO one Bel bu one road the BR
project they're able to uh access Europe
by via
land but India doesn't have any access
India is essentially completely cut off
it's almost like a landlocked country
you know on the North you have Chinese
occupied Tibet to the West you have
Pakistan and Pakistan occupied Kashmir
and in the East you have Burma which is
under Civil War kind of situation so
India's completely cut off the only
access India has for other nations is
either by air or by sea and India hasn't
really developed it Port Port system and
its Maritime prowess so that's the only
access India has essentially to the rest
of the world is by air or by shipping so
now if you have a port over here which
you control the chabahar port then what
you can do is you can bypass Pakistan
entirely and uh send and receive
shipments via the west coast probably
from mumai and other ports through
chabahar and then you can send ship
shipments into Afghanistan you can sh
send shipments into Eurasia there is the
international north north south
transport Corridor that India is part of
which will connect the port of Mumbai to
the port of Baku in aeran where aeran
doesn't have an economy as such it is
entirely dependent on
oil and uh and we can also connect India
to Russia via the international north
south transport Corridor and so
on so cha Bahar is a port that will
facilitate this it's going to be a
patchwork kind of route from Mumbai to
chahar or from the west coast of India
to chabahar you will send stuff and
receive stuff by by C through shipping
channels and from chahar you can have a
ra Rail Link to a place called zahedan
over here and from zahedan into
Afghanistan you can send stuff and you
can also have other routes which will
take you to Baku and the Caucasus region
the South Caucasus region Armenia aeran
Georgia Etc and then you have Southern
Russia over there and you can also
access uh Europe if you want through
this so that's why it's kind of a game
Cher for the for the past seven eight
decades India has been deprived of its
historical traditional access to Central
Asia and Eurasia and now we can depend
on
Iran and uh get this done so it's kind
of a long circuitous kind of route but
at least it kind of restores India's
access to Central Asia and Eurasia via
Iran which is why India will have to
depend on Iran for this now why would
Iran do such a thing well it also gives
gives Iran uh options right uh Iran
already has a strategic strategic
agreement with China Iran has good
relations with Russia and this is a
trans shipment route that will
eventually connect India with Russia as
well so it all works out to every
nation's benefit not very for China but
definitely for India and Iran and Russia
and various other nations that are
connected through this so the these are
the benefits of the chabahar port deal
for India it essentially restores
India's historical access to Central
Asia in Europe after a gap of almost
eight eight or so decades so that's why
it's important it's good for the Indian
economy India is a rising economy India
is a growing economy India in the next
couple of years we'll become A5 trillion
doll economy India wants to be the
manufacturing Hub of the world to have
that you need extremely good and
resilient and reliable Supply
chains and trade routes and diverse
diverse Supply chains and trade routes
so by doing this India ensures that it
has multiple options of by which it can
send shipments to various parts of the
world that's why it is important for
India okay next question is by danush
thoughts on Putin's visit to China how
should India see this development given
that Russia is China is India's biggest
arms
supplier would Russia side with China in
the event of an India China Conflict by
stop arms to Russia to
India okay that's an interesting
question so Putin has recently visited
China he went to China and I'm sure he's
back to Moscow by
now and Mr Putin chose to visit China
chose China as the first place that he
would visit after his recent election
Victory so that kind of gives you an
idea of the kind of uh importance that
Mr Putin uh gives to his relationship
his nation's relationship with China and
his personal relationship with Shi
Jinping so Mr Putin visited China he
brought along his economic adviser the
in various economic officials and maybe
some military officials as well defense
officials so the relationship between
Russia and China right now is all about
the economy and uh military and defense
and a bit of trade and there's a
significant asymmetry between Russia and
China these days when it comes to the
economy and the trade so China is a much
much larger economy compared to Russia
Russia economically is smaller than is
not even in the top 10 Nations Russia
obviously is the second most powerful
military Nation especially when you
consider its gigantic nuclear weapons
Arsenal and The Delivery Systems it has
and the kind of uh reach it has across
Eurasia because of its inherent
size so Russia is has the upper hand
militarily China has the upper
significantly upper hand economically
when it comes to the two Nations and the
trade uh about a third of Russia 's
trade is with China but when it comes to
China only about 4% of its trade is with
Russia so there's a massive asymmetry
there so historically Russia used to be
the USSR used to be the senior partner
China was the junior partner then you
had the sinos Soviet split which began
in the what 50s 60s 70s it end well it
became very much official essentially in
the 70s but uh the relationship between
Russia and China has never been better
since the Sino Soviets split and now the
roles are kind of reversed Russia is the
senior partner especially economically
and uh the West has sought to isolate Mr
Putin isolate Russia economically by by
launching bucket loads of sanctions on
Russia so Russia depends more on China
these days and China uses that as a
massive leverage to extract concessions
from Russia so China overall has the
upper hand and Russia needs China more
than China needs Russia and that's why
you can see that Mr Putin his language
his demeanor Etc was very conciliatory
very uh you know that sort of thing when
he was in Beijing and Mr XI junping was
more of
the you could say big brother kind of
you know he had adopted the big brother
kind of role so you can see uh the
dynamic between the two Nations it has
kind of reversed in the past 10 15 years
right now the question you're asking so
so the danger always from Russia's
perspective is is that it becomes a
vasal of China and that is something
they do obviously do not
want Russia the dependence is bad for
Russia the dependence on China and China
supplies Russia Russia supplies China
with crude materials essential
Commodities raw materials oil gas
petroleum whatever else and China
supplies Russia with finished products
you know drone engines and washing
machines and whatnot okay that's the
kind of relationship the two countries
have and uh this dominance that China
has currently in the relationship it's
not good for Russia and I'm sure Mr
Putin doesn't like it but right now
there are few options especially given
the war in Ukraine and the the West's
attempts to isolate Russia so the danger
is that Russia becomes a vasal of China
and that is something which can only be
offset if Russia has some other options
Russia needs options apart from China
and one of the options is India so India
is Russia has now become probably
India's largest supplier of oil and that
is good for Russia because it tells you
that it means Russia has options apart
from China and overall if you look at uh
Eurasia especially Eastern Eurasia which
means Asia the only nation in Asia that
can actually counterbalance China apart
from Russia is India and that's why
India is important for Russia so to
ensure that China doesn't doesn't you
know just right rough shot over
everybody the only nation that can
counterbalance China to some extent is
India and India is growing India's
econom is growing if it keeps growing
for 20 years it can be a genuine threat
from the Chinese perspective the way
they see it they see everything as a
threat so Russia uh sees its
relationship with India also with a
great deal of importance now the
question is if there's a war between
Russia between India and China what will
Russia do first of all the West will
most likely not come to India's Aid as
I've explained in the previous previous
video they'll try and extract
concessions and use that as leverage
against India what will Russia do well
Russia also is not in a position right
now to intervene and uh you know
intervene militarily especially take
India's CH again side against China and
go and do anything against China
militarily that's not in Russia's
interests so if there's a war between
India and China Russia will urge
restrained and say that please go back
to the negotiating table and settle your
differences there
and I do not see well the Chinese will
certainly try and
uh uh coer Russia let's say into
stopping arms supplies to India that is
certainly something that will happen the
Chinese will try and do that so then the
pressure will be in Russia because
Russia does want India Russia kind of
wants the status quo the way it is right
now China India Russia the kind of
relationship is there trial relationship
Russia is okay with that
Russia doesn't want the relationship to
get uh to change too much uh so if China
fights a war with India and if Russia
believes that India may be defeated then
it will certainly not want that to
happen uh so the pressure will be in
Russia as to what it does the Chinese
will say stop sending all arms whatever
you're sending to India stop it entirely
what does Russia do I think Russia will
need to demonstrate some fortitude and
some Independence in in such a scenario
because it is in Russia's interest that
India does well against China and India
is not you know defeated by China so
these are all hypotheticals but uh yeah
it will if such a thing happens it's
going to be a big test of Russia's
fortitude and
Independence page Bora says IND is India
much worthy to claim a permanent seat in
the United Nations and if not what
should India's future steps be for this
and also what's your view of on China's
military activity around Taiwan is it a
trailer before a full
War okay so is India worthy to claim to
put its case forth for a permanent seat
in the United Nations security Council
well let's look at the makeup of the
United Nations security Council the five
permanent members okay let's let's see
who they are the US the sole superpower
secondly there's Russia which is a near
super power militarily but economically
not that powerful thirdly you have China
which is a gigantic economy but not
clearly as powerful econ uh militarily
as Russia or the US these three nations
make sense the three most powerful
Nations let's say hard power then you
have a nation like France and you have a
nation like the UK what is the UK I'll
tell you what the UK is okay the the UK
is a poor Third Rate Nation attached to
London the real economy of the UK is
London London is the global moneya
laundering Hub and you could say the
financial capital of Europe one of the
major Financial outposts and hubs of the
Western
Empire and so London is what really
matters and the rest of the nation is a
poor Third Rate Nation attached to
London and it it it it no longer has any
geopolitical pretentions it's not even a
second r geopolitical power it's a third
rate geopolitical power it doesn't even
have control the UK over its own nuclear
weapons okay which are which are M to
American ballistic missiles which means
that the big red button isn't in London
with Mr Rishi sunak it's probably
somewhere in in Washington DC somewhere
around that place so the UK is is
doesn't really belong in the United
Nations security Council what about
France well France again is a member of
NATO which means it's not entirely
Sovereign NATO has R sovereignty which
means some of your National sovereignty
goes goes out of your hands and it
becomes the domain of the NATO High
command so France obviously doesn't like
this it's the only nation in NATO that
has a quazi independent foreign policy
I've said this so many times but
economically it's not that big it does
have some power projection ability
because of its Colonial possessions in
the Indian Ocean region and its
influence over certain parts of France
especially where sorry certain parts of
Africa especially
northern and western Africa but uh
overall you could say it's a hasbean
kind of nation okay much of its wealth
still is extracted Out of Africa and so
on so when it comes to the UK and France
they they don't they don't really belong
in the UN Security Council given their
current status the current state of
their power their economy the military
and overall hard power not really and
India's economy is larger than that of
France and of the UK and India is a
rising geopolitical power India
dominates the Indian Ocean region I
think India
deserves a place in the UN Security
Council much more than the UK or France
I mean the world has changed it's no
longer 1945 but the UN Security Council
is a snapshot of the world order as it
was in
1945 so uh I think India should uh keep
on reminding the world that it is an
injustice and a travesty that India is
not a member permanent member of the UN
Security Council keep on reiterating
this at every occasion but don't worry
too much about it because the UN is
becoming more and more irrelevant okay
it's obviously lot lost a lot of respect
so what India needs to do future steps
is just keep on growing your economy and
as your economy grows your military
might grows and work on the power
projection abilities which means you
need you need a powerful navy you need
to invest in the Navy in distributed
lethality over a wide surface are area
of the Indian Ocean region that's what
India needs to do keep working acidly on
this day in and day out and the next 5
years it will be a different story in 10
years it'll be a much more different
story that's what India needs to do now
what's my view on China's military
activity around Taiwan is it a trailer
before a full
War okay let's take a look at the
Chinese Tha military activity so we're
talking about the South China Sea which
which historically was called the Champa
Sea and the East China Sea or whatever
that is in the Philippine Sea all of
this so China claims the whole of the
South China Sea why are the 9 or 10 or
11 or whatever dash line they have of
late and there's a lot of military
activity around Taiwan so China
essentially has encircled Taiwan VI its
Navy China has a very extensive Navy
numerically the largest Navy in the
world in terms of numbers and China
repeatedly transgresses around upon CH
upon Tha taiwan's uh
territorial uh airspace via its fighter
planes and bombers and whatnot so that
is something that's become very normal
China has completely normal normalized
these activities military Naval
exercises around Taiwan and the
transgression into Taiwanese airspace
via Chinese Air Force assets that's
completely normal and it's a routine
occurrence every week almost every day
this is something that goes on so yeah
that is the situ ation when it comes to
Taiwan is this a trailer before a full
War uh that remains to be seen okay so
uh It is believed that shi Jinping when
he came to power he had given so he came
to power I believe in 2012 if I'm not
mistaken and it is believed that he had
given the Armed Forces of China 15 years
so he had given them a deadline of 2027
by when they need to be completely fully
100% ready to U undertake an invasion of
Taiwan on demand so in 2024 2027 is 3
years away so what is the state of
affairs the the Chinese now have a
second aircraft carrier that they are
testing out second or third whichever it
is the leing was there and the so
they're testing out a new super carrier
880,000 ton aircraft carrier which is
kind of comparable to the 100,000 ton US
aircraft carriers so you could say it's
the first world class aircraft carrier
they have a super carrier kind of
category and they are testing it out so
um are they ready to take an to
undertake and prosecute a successful
Invasion and conquest of Taiwan well
only they would know they would know the
full assessment of their
capabilities but if they invade Taiwan
they will need to fight the US and Japan
and South Korea at the same time okay so
it is a very big undertaking and are
they ready we don't know only shenping
and his people know and uh yeah but one
thing is clear that Taiwan is soon going
to face an existential crisis an
existential event in its uh history
probably in the second half of the 2020s
and pro if not then then in the in the
first half of the 2030s that's going to
happen sooner or later unless China
undergo some drastic decline that we
have not
foreseen okay pram Sharma says why is
China and various other central banks
why are they buying huge amounts of gold
is there a connection to the US dollar
losing its value and possibly the US
dollar with gold and other
Commodities yeah so uh lots of central
banks lots of Nations have been
purchasing gold India has been doing
that China is purchasing tremendous
amounts of gold uh I think China has
been purchasing large amounts of gold
the past 16 17 months almost every month
they're spending a billion dollars or so
on on
gold and uh yeah so what does it mean
China is not only stocking up on gold it
is stockpiling all kinds of essential
commodities like oil and iron ore and
copper and Cobalt and various rare
Earths and whatnot everything you can
imagine nuclear weapons ha uh grain or
and food materials China is stockpiling
everything so when do you when when does
somebody stockpile stuff in this manner
remember the horrible days of the 2020s
early 2020s 2020 21 22 the pandemic the
lockdowns everybody has gone through
this you would stockpile all non-p
perishable able food items you would
stockpile tinned Foods you know I mean
depending on where you are in the West
in the US people were stockpiling tons
of toilet paper so when you're
stockpiling it indicates you your
mindset that you you feel like you're
under siege and you feel like it's a
very abnormal situation out there and
the the future could be dangerous and
bad that's when you stockpile stuff so
why is China stockpiling everything it
could indicate that they may be
preparing for war when it comes to well
the only War what are the possib
possible Wars that China could fight one
is uh an invasion of Taiwan second is
take know conquer various Philippine
islands and Japanese islands in the
South and East China Sea that's the
second war China could fight and the
third war it could fight would could be
with India in the Himalayas so it's
either India it's either the South and E
East China Sea versus Philippines and
Japan or it's Taiwan so these are the
three possibilities which one is correct
we don't know no but yes it's not just
China it's many other nations that are
stockpiling various kinds of things
especially gold so uh there is always
the fear when it comes to any
responsible nation that it's very well
known that the U US dollar is a paper
currency it's a fiat currency it doesn't
have any real value the only strength
that the US dollar has it it depends
entirely on the US military strength and
the US ability to project power across
the world and that is the only thing
that keeps the US dollar the world's
Reserve currency so yeah I mean it is
always always good to take precautions
okay and yeah obviously if you have
significant reserves of gold it means
that your currency also has some actual
value that backs it up so these are the
reasons why you are doing this and
there's always the danger of future
economic shocks and economic downturn
the global economy isn't doing very well
lots of nations are in are entering a
phase of phase of recession or near
recession economic growth globally is
stagnant and sluggish India is the only
bright spot out there but India also has
to take precautions so yeah that is the
global overall scenario right
now okay Balan says is the Indian
government somewhere under the influence
of the Chinese government the reality
apparently is that we have lost our land
near the Lac but the government did
nothing except giving speeches sir it
looks like you have been listening to
certain YouTubers
yes India has lost land but at what time
near the La India lost land in the 1950s
and 196 especially in 1962 that's when
Mr neeru did not take care of the
Indian you know National Security and
defense and India ended up giving lots
of land aiin and other other parts of
the Northern Territories to
China so that what that is something
that happened during the time of Mr Neo
and then later on on there was this
policy this absurd policy of the Indian
governments several governments after Mr
Nero to not develop any in
infrastructure in the northern border
regions and the Chinese kept on Rel
relentlessly developing infrastructure
which gave them a significant advantage
and that is that is something we are
trying to offset now with our
infrastructure building efforts so after
62 also the Chinese kept on salami
slicing away at Indian Territory inch by
inch inch by inch maybe sometimes a foot
by foot or two here and there some times
a kilometer so yes land has been lost
but not during the time of Mr Narendra
Modi but un but if you watch certain
YouTubers and certain such people well
you're going to end up believing this
you see and you will you will recall
that it's after Mr Modi came to power
that the Chinese uh the Chinese uh
so-called people's Liberation Army
started clashing with the Indian army in
the Border regions why was that because
now for the first time IND the India the
Indian armed forces were given the
Liberty to push back against China and
not you know give into Chinese
provocations and India started building
significant amounts of Border
infrastructure go out there go up there
in the north you will see that the
Border roads organization bro is active
day and light night whether it is good
weather or Terrible Weather whe whether
it's snowing or freezing they are active
day and night they're building
infrastructure on a 24hour 365 days
basis and that is what has rattled China
that's why you had the do CL Incident
That's why you have the various other
incidents the gwan incident various
clashes that are happening it's because
India is pushing back so whatever land
India has lost was lost before Mr Mod's
government came to power but that is
something and and the the political
parties that are responsible for this
are trying to create a narrative where
it looks like this land was lost because
of Mr Modi when it happened before Mr
Modi ever came to power in Delhi so uh
but yes that's the narrative that
YouTubers and certain individuals and
political parties and all are trying to
create that we are losing land in the
North in the LSC and the government is
doing nothing except giving speeches you
have to understand what the reality is
all
right okay Harel Agarwal nice display
picture uh okay the question is how did
the US allow its European wasal to join
the BR the Chinese belt and rout
initiative project initially okay so
when it comes to the European nations
Central Asian Nations there are about 35
Nations that were or are part of the
Chinese brri a whole bunch of these are
in the central Asia region the Caucasus
region you have usbekistan kazakistan
Tajikistan kyrgistan Nations like aeran
this is mainly Central Asia and the
Caucasus region right and then you have
a whole bunch of Eastern European
nations or Caucasus Nations like Armenia
like bellarus like Albania Bosnia
heroina Bulgaria mova Montenegro Russia
Romania Czech Republic uh turkey Ukraine
Etc there are members of who have joined
the belt and Road initiative turkey is a
member of NATO which is kind of you
could say a proper us wasal but Serbia
is not a US wasal mova is not a us wasal
uh Hungary well Czech Republic Bulgaria
not really very much Bosnia heroina
well it depends right Slovenia Russia is
Russia us wasal uh and so on when it
comes to the actual Western European
nations EU Nations
Austria is a member of the BR uh and and
and less important Nations like well
with all due respect Cyprus Greece
Luxembourg North Macedonia Italy Italy
has pulled out of the brri they have
withdra from the B and there was
announced by Madame milone after the G20
Summit in Delhi so it's not really like
there's a whole lot of EU members that
have joined the
BR and it's not like there's a whole lot
of NATO members that have joined the B
The Only Exception I I would say is
turkey and probably Austria Austria is
it a member of NATO Greece is a member
of NATO yeah Greece is a member of NATO
so that's just a couple of Nations and
overall these nations are not going to
sell out their National interest or the
interest of of NATO or the EU to China
it's about gaining and acing benefits
rather than giving any real uh anything
really uh genuine or significant in
return and it's also good to have your
own people in the enemy camp sometimes
right so yeah overall that's what's the
deal has been what the deal has been
it's not like the Chinese have taken
over these nations or anything most of
these nations are a me are members of
the bra only in name there's not really
been any real infrastructure development
and say many of these I mean one example
is Pakistan what happened to the CPC
China Pakistan economic Corridor some of
it was built some of the projects were
abandoned and right now it's completely
well nothing's happening so there you
have it
yeah okay rodrit sarar says why did the
US and its satellite states allow German
reunification to happen in 1990 despite
knowing how was unified Germany made
their life hell in the two World Wars
well you have to understand that after
1945 Germany became a nation that was
entirely I mean West Germany see what
happened in 1945 is that Germany was
partitioned okay the eastern half the
Eastern portion not half Eastern portion
map we have to show the map where's the
map okay let's take a look at the map of
Germany so Germany is in Europe Europe
yes this is Germany so in 19 19 45 what
happened is that Germany was partitioned
the Eastern portion became well a member
of
the Soviet satellite States and the
Western portion became a member of the
US satellite States so the Eastern
portion was under Soviet occupation you
could say and the Western portion was
under us occupation now when it comes to
West Germany its Constitution was
written under the supervision of the US
not a single word was such that the US
would not would be unhappy with it so
essentially the whole nation is under US
military occupation you still have US
military bases on German
territory and uh the nation it's it's
the situation is very similar to that of
Japan similar but dissimilar there are
differences but overall Germany is under
the same status uh even today it's under
US military occupation permanent US
military occupation so that was a
situation in uh the early 90s when the
uh Berlin Wall came down and the
downfall of the USSR happened so then
what happened is that the US got the
chance to grab even East Germany and
make it a region under its occupation so
why would you not do that it's not like
Germany is an independent nation with
independent foreign policy and
independent economic policy and an
independent military policy absolutely
not absolutely not they are completely
under the control of the us whether you
realize it or not so the US got the
opportunity to expand its uh power
projection eastwards by grabbing by by
incorporating East Germany and into West
Germany and reunifying the nation so it
gave the US a larger area which it could
control completely and then we know that
we had the Eastward expansion of NATO
the Relentless Eastward expansion of
NATO which eventually culminated in the
current War that's going on in Ukraine
so that's why the Americans were
perfectly F fine with this that the
satellite state of the US have no say in
what the US does by the way okay it's
only the US that decides what happens so
that's why the US very was very happy
with Germany reunification Germany is
not an independent autonomous Nation by
any means look at the kind of
immigration that's been happening in
Germany yeah you think any any truly
independent German government or or
Chancellor would allow the sort of
immigration to happen unchecked
immigration from God knows what nations
only military age males who have no
respect or or liking for German culture
yeah so you see that's the deal so the
yeah the US worries about the prospect
of a strong Germany it's it constantly
worries about that I mean Germany is
firmly under their control but you
cannot it's it's hard to shake off the
memory of those those Hugo Boss uniforms
and those marching boots so it makes
sense to weaken Germany and you can see
the weakening of Germany Germany is
giving up on its nuclear reactors it's
now firing up its cold its cold power
plants the northstream pipeline has been
sabotaged Germany no longer gets the
cheap gas it was getting from Russia
which is why Germany has gone under into
a recession and so on so yes Germany is
getting weakened the the demographics
will be further let's say destabilized
with
the influx of uh random immigrants not
random very specifically targeted
immigrants from West Asia as well as
Africa so yeah well so Germany is
totally under control and there's no
threat eventually there'll be no threat
left in Germany sadly from the German
perspective okay this is a long question
prianka Tanja says there's something I
find hard to understand just like we in
India want to and are attempting to
isolate Pakistan being the state sponsor
of terrorism and expect the other
nations to understand our pretty comment
with a Pakistan and engage with them
accordingly Israel to is the victim of
terrorism at the hands of Iran sponsored
proxies and expects other countries
including India to deal with Iran in in
an appropriate way after considering our
Zero Tolerance towards terrorism
terrorism and talks can't go hand inand
why do we treat Iran like a normal
nation and wish to streamline our
relationship with it I understand we
have our interest in circumventing
Pakistan to get access to Afghanistan
and Central Asia but being the states
sponsors of terrorism why don't we treat
the same way Iran the same way as we
treat Pakistan
when we expect others to have zero
tolerance towards terrorism why do we
support a nation that unleashes Terror
on others okay so the Assumption behind
this question is that Iran is a genuine
State sponsor of terrorism right so Iran
is our neighboring country not not right
now temporarily not but yes historically
our neighboring
Nation now now let's let's talk about
terrorism what is Terrorism terrorism is
what India has experienced for several
decades ades Pakistan Unleashed
terrorism on India and let's remember
who financed and funded the terrorism it
was the United States for several
decades we know what happened to Kashmir
the exod US of the Kashmir native Hindus
who are still living like as as refugees
in other other parts of India right so
that also happened through US sponsored
Pakistani terrorism so we know what
Pakistani terrorism is like we know what
terrorism is like now when somebody
makes the claim that Iran is a state
sponsor of terrorism please I would like
to know where is Iranian where are those
Iranian suicide bombers where are those
Iranian terrorists we know what
Pakistani terrorists look like we have
seen so so many of them you know uh they
end up flat on their faces on the
streets with uh with with traumatic
damage on their body when they
eventually meet the Indian Armed Forces
we know what terrorism looks like we
know what Pakistani terrorist looks like
we know what Isis terrorists look like
we know what Al-Qaeda terrorists look
like do where are those Iranian
terrorists and where are they doing
those suicide bombings and whatever else
and in which nation are they doing it
you know when you uh the problem is that
the entire media is controlled by the
west and that's why they can label Any
Nation the state sponsor of this or
that okay so Iran is just like any
self-respecting
nation that has Ambitions geopolitical
Ambitions seeks to uh expand its power
projection abilities which means that it
it leverages the the assets that it has
developed in Iraq doesn't mean that
these are terrorist attacks or terrorist
assets it has assets and it has a good
relationship with the nation of Syria it
has a good relationship with Russia
Russia with with Yemen and so on and
when
Iran plays the game of geopolitical
power projection the Americans will
label that as having terrorist proxies
when the Americans use
Isis against the nation of Syria those
are what what do they call them moderate
Rebels when the US employs Al-Qaeda to
fight the Syrian government and unleash
hell on the people on the yazidis and
whatnot including Isis that is those are
moderate Rebels when the when the whole
nation of Iraq is devastated more than a
million people die under the bombs well
that is Liberation it's democracy we
have to understand what terrorism really
really is and is Iran really a terrorist
nation and then we have to understand
that every nation has its own interests
and the one job of the leader and the
government of a nation is to further
your nation's National interest that all
that is all it is and this is something
we were taught by our well not sure he
was everyone's ancestor but Mr chanaka
vishnugupta chanak
he taught us this and it is part of our
heritage so we should remember that the
world
is
not a very nice place the world is a
harsh place it's it's a Cutthroat world
every nation looks out for itself think
of the global geopolitical scene as a
big fish tank in you in which you have
th thousands of fish different kinds of
fish some fish will join together and
and work together other fish will be too
large and they will try to eat them and
so on it's constant cooperation and
competition it's simply the law of the
Jungle that's how geopolitics works okay
and every nation whoever is the leader
has only one job you serve your nation
and your
people so when it comes to the leader of
India his job is to serve the people of
India and the nation of India and that's
all and sometimes you may have to let
let me give you an
example how many of you remember that a
few years ago the daughter of the uh
Sultan of Dubai the the Amir of Dubai
whatever his name is the daughter her
her name was
not okay I forget the name of the lady
she
escaped from uh
Dubai by a by a boat or or or yacht or
something and she wanted to take refuge
in India okay and she was her ship was
of
her her uh yacht was off the coast of
Goa so the Sultan of uh Dubai calls up
Mr Modi says that I am facing this
problem my daughter has run away and
it's a terrible embarrassment to me and
my family can you please do something
about it okay and this lady the the
princess she apparently it seems that
her father was very cruel to her and she
wanted to to escape and she thought that
India will give her shelter and what Mr
Modi did was that he asked the Indian
coast guard to intercept this vessel
take the lady into custody and
repatriate her back to her father okay
so that's what in Mr Modi did now it is
entirely possible I don't know that
maybe she was right and maybe she she
wanted to flee from her nation and get
Refuge elsewhere but when it comes to
the National interest we want to have
good relations with our friends in the
UAE and when such a request comes in you
exceed to the
request I'm sure it's it's it's sad for
the lady I sometimes I I would say it's
s sad for her I feel so sorry for her
but what Mr Modi did was in his own
nation's
interest and that that was obviously a
considerable filp to the relation
relationship between India and the UAE
and in Dubai and in in a week or two
later the Dubai extradited a known
terrorist back to India okay that's how
it works so you have to put your
nation's interest first um I do not
believe that Iran is a state sponsor of
terrorism as the West claims and India
has and Iran has done absolutely nothing
to hurt India's national interests it's
actually the US that is hurting India's
national interest by by prohibiting IND
India from uh buying Iranian gas and oil
I mean Iran is right next door imagine
how much cheaper it will be to get oil
just from Iran but no we can't do it
because of the US sanctions and US
threats and arm
twisting so I don't see Iran as a SP
State sponsor of terrorism Iran is not a
terrorist Nation any in in any way
compared to the way Pakistan
is and India has to look out for its own
interests and people will say that why
do you why is India Cooperative with the
Taliban the Taliban are so harsh on
their women it's not my problem okay and
it's not the problem of the Indian
leadership and the in the Indian
government what happens in Afghanistan
inside there is their own business it's
none of our business if their people
have a problem with the Taliban and the
way it is governing the nation they can
take it up with the Taliban leadership
if the ladies and the girls of
Afghanistan are unhappy they should go
and talk to the to the leaders of the
country but we as a nation Sovereign
Nation will deal with Afghanistan as a
different another Sovereign Nation in a
mutually beneficial Manner and same goes
with Iran so we have to understand that
that we have to be realistic and
pragmatic in international relations
there is no place for Morality and
ethics the only morality of a king is
that his kingdom and its people should
prosper so yeah that's how I that's how
it
is uh Iran for from our perspective is a
normal Nation it is a nation with which
we want to have good relations and I do
not see Iran as a state sponsor of
terrorism despite whatever the Western
media claims and the in various Western
Nations
claim okay rodra jit sarar says why did
the vietnames liberate Cambodia from the
hands of popot what were their interests
okay let's go back to the map where is
Cambodia my dear friends oh the map has
already adjusted itself so we know where
we are India yes let's go eastwards we
cross the Sea of Kalinga we go eastwards
and then then we have swabi which is
Thailand and you go east of swabi you
have
Cambodia and this entire region
southeast Asia was once very very very
very very
indianized they were all Hindus and some
of them later became Buddhists and even
today you see more of our culture there
they in India they are more more
culturally Indian than us Indians anyway
that's a different story why am I
talking about that okay Cambodia so what
happened in Cambodia I think it was the
in the mid 70s that the K Rouge the red
kares uh Marxist communist organization
supported by China these guys they
fought a Civil War in Cambodia and they
took over the nation the city the
capital city of
fnend fell to the uh the Rouge and then
these people they Unleashed a horrific
wave of Terror and genocide on their own
people they emptied all the cities they
forced everybody to go out into the
countryside and do forced labor there
were brutal executions I mean I don't
even want to talk about it okay how bad
it was and uh you will see this reaction
from me because as a kid I happened to I
was in a barber shop one day as a kid I
don't know 10 years old or something
okay in in in Europe and uh when you are
waiting in a barber shop for your turn
you know there are magazines around
there there's this magazine sitting
there and I pick up the magazine I open
it and there's these pictures of the
countryside of Cambodia in the aftermath
of the Vietnamese liberation of the
nation and my goodness the image is
there of the dead people ah horrific for
a kid to
see so what the May Rouge did was they
killed off I don't know how many million
2 million 3 million of their own people
in the most horrific ways the most
atrocious the most cruel ways now the K
rouj was a proxy of China you see the
Chinese was the K Rouge not a genocidal
terrorist organization it was entirely
supported by China it was a proxy of
China people uh we believe that Iran
some of us believe that Iran is a state
sponsor of terrorism and all that I mean
what about
China Iran is not China is anyway so the
kir rou was a proxy of China okay now
what was happening was that they took
over the whole of the nation of Cambodia
and then they were also attacking
Vietnamese Villages across the border
and there was this big influx of
refugees who were desperately freeing
fleeing from the K Rouge and these
refugees would spill over either into
Thailand or into Vietnam okay so Vietnam
eventually got fed up okay especially
because the K Rouge were violating the
Border uh and the sovereignty of the
nation and attack vietnames Villages and
so on So eventually what they did was
that they launched Air Raids and they
sent the Army across the border and and
over time they liberated Cambodia from
the K Rouge and Vietnam were supported
by the way by the
USSR so this Invasion or liberation of
Cambodia by Vietnam happened I think in
1979 all right so Vietnam was supported
by the USSR and comod was supported by
China I mean the k rou terrorists
genocidal evil people were supported by
China so this was an
extension of the sinos Soviet
split China and the USSR had become kind
of enemies especially after the 1969
usuri River clashes and then the
eventual opening up of China to the US
so China became a US proxy you could say
to for some for some time and obviously
the USSR did not like that and then
spilled over into this region in
Southeast Asia so Vietnam was Pro USSR
supported by the USSR and the K rou were
supported by China so the Vietnamese
Army prevailed they kicked the K rou out
and the K rou retreated into the jungles
and so on and Cambodia became a
Socialist Communist country called
cucha and it was called campuchia until
I think the early 1990s or something and
then Mr hunen came to power and well
long story so Vietnam had these
interests it was also kind of you could
say a spilling over of the China USSR
rivalry into the Southeast Asian region
and in response for Vietnam destroying
the government of the pro-china K rouj
the Chinese decided to teach Vietnam a
lesson and they invaded Vietnam from the
North in 1979 or 1980 somewhere around
that time and the Vietnam is defeated
China the Chinese lost to Vietnam so the
last last time the Chinese tried to
invade another Nation they were beaten
and defeated by a small nation called
Vietnam there you have
it Sund Gupta
says what's your view on Sam petr's
comments that Indians look like Arab
white Chinese
Africans this individual Mr pitroda he
was once a big deal somehow in India he
was the adviser to very powerful people
I think in the 1980s '90s or something
out that time and he still seems to have
delusions of grander of some kind so
what did Mr Peta say he said that
Indians from the West part of India they
look like
Arabs North Indians from Northern India
they look like white people uh people
from Eastern India look Chinese and
people from Southern India look African
that's what Mr Puda claimed so using
that logic uh I would be an Arab yeah do
do I look Arabic by the way so I would
be an Arab Mr Gandhi Mr mandas Gandhi
apparently was Arab Mr M what what
mandas Muhammad Gina was also an Arab
apparently Imran Khan what is it he's a
white
man who else who else is a white man can
you think of any other Northern North
Indian people who are the famous North
Indians uh so I I am like like Z like
zero says here Habibi
[Laughter]
abijit uh North Indians who are the
famous North Indians in India Mr Neu oh
Mr Neu was a white
man kangana R out is a white
[Laughter]
lady uh okay so so Mr Neu was a white
man uh Miss Kang R out was is a white
lady who else do we
have then down south
uh who Mr Muran is is African apparently
Mr Ravi Chand Ashwin is is African who
else did we have in in in South South
India I can't think of any right now uh
and according to Mr Peta Mr Bose subash
Chandra BOS was what Chinese are you
kidding me Mr Peta
seriously Mr kamam Dr apj Abdul kamam
what was he African are you kidding me
I just don't get these people who make
these ridiculous comments irresponsible
comments so yeah yeah good to take this
question it it introduces a bit of
hilarity and levity in this in this
episode okay next
question this is by Happy Faces 2 to8
why do most historians think that humans
became civilized from hunter gatherers
to crop cultivators just around 10,000
BC Al they can't go beyond 1,500 BC when
it comes to history how can human
history be so short how can we evolve so
rapidly human civilization should be
tens of thousands of years old I'll tell
you what these historians that we are
referring to over here well who wrote
All the history today you have
historians in India you have historians
in other countries but
the the groundwork the foundation of the
history which they use is all by
European historians it was all written
by European historians and whatever they
wrote in the 18th 19th 20th century that
is taken as self-evident and that's the
entire Foundation of all historical
research and writing that happens today
and if you disagree with that then you
are regarded as as what a crackpot a
conspiracy theorist or whatever so all
of these all of this history was written
by Europeans by the West it's all
eurocentric history and the problem is
that in Europe there was no history
essentially
before uh 1500 BC it all starts with uh
well the Mediterranean region Greece and
even when Greece was emerging as a
civilization the rest of Europe was what
hunter gatherers living in caves eating
wild animals living in trees is through
is through I not lie you
see so European history begins around
1500 BC so then they want to force fit
that on everybody else because the
the Inconvenient Truth is that India has
a history that goes back at least 10,000
years China has a history that goes back
three 4,000 years Africa we don't even
know what their history is because it's
been totally destroyed the Native
Americans the thex the Mayas the azk and
whoever else the chimu the Moshe they
had the civilizations that went back
thousands of years it's the Europeans
who are the
youngest in the the latest the last to
become somewhat civilized so they want
to Force fit that that that time period
that that chronology on everybody else
that nobody dare be civilized before
1500 BC that's what they do if you look
at various Monumental pieces of
monumental architecture there is goeke
in Anatolia currently part of turkey for
some for some time so if you go to go go
it's believed to be about 10 goes goes
back to about 10,000 BC or 8,000 BC
whatever 10,000 11,000 years old and
that clearly is that that um that site
that archaeological site it clearly
served some kind of religious purpose
and it was like not a small site at all
so it was clearly intelligent evolved
people they
understood architecture they had some
understanding of of science at least a
little bit and clearly more advanced
than the Europeans of 1500 BC is true so
yeah so that's why they they don't want
to recognize this now when it comes to
not just go they pay right uh okay
where's map where is map we should see
map so here is map even in India if you
go so in in Tamil
Nadu where is puducheri puducheri
puducheri and south of puducherry there
is
a where is that little
village I must find
it
okay okay so somewhere south of
puducheri there is uh off the coast of
Tamil Nadu uh archaeologists have
discovered a giant underwater city okay
probably cavari pum
pattinam of the suum literature era and
that city is at a depth that indicates
that it was last above water about
10,000 years ago 10,000 years ago okay
that's in the east of India of the coast
now when it comes to
the west coast of India we have dwarka
we know that there there is an
underwater city of dwarka and that also
dates back about 8 10,000 years and when
it comes to the Gulf of kbat
archaological complex it's a whole
complex of multiple cities that are all
under the ocean okay and they were last
above the ocean about 10 12,000 years
ago so uh that tells you how ancient
Indian civilization is the problem is
that India's archeologist seem to be
working hand hand in glove with these
anti-india elements in the in the
historical academic fraternity and they
are ensuring that they don't excav this
and they don't throw light on the
Antiquity of Indian civilization so I'll
tell you what you are absolutely right
happy faces 228 that in the human
history is very ancient it's not just
1500 BC That civilization emerged it's
not just 10,000 BC that agriculture
evolved we know that India had
agriculture 177,000 years ago it is
known it is demonstrated it is proven I
don't know the sources right now look it
up look it
up okay this is homework for you for
those who say that I don't bring sources
I'm doing a live stream over here I'm
taking questions on the Fly I cannot
show you all the sources otherwise half
my time will be will go in doing that do
some due diligence do some homework find
your own sources I'm telling you what
sources exist okay Indian agriculture is
at least 17,000 years old minimum and
and much more so all these claim all
these narratives they they serve certain
purpose to put forth the eurocentric and
Euros supremacist version of
History okay Priyanka Tanja says could
you please shed light some light on the
curse of the Pharaohs especially totin
and the Mystery that revolves around the
death of the excavators who Unearthed
his tomb please share your insights so
tutun hamun is one of these Egyptian
kings Egyptian pharaohs I believe his
tomb was Unearthed and discovered in the
valley let's go to the
map uh always nice to see the map and
discover new places so uh this is
alq Cairo and where is the Valley of the
Kings let's let's just search for the
Valley of the
Kings
exor
Mis and let's zoom in let's go
here we go whoopsy
dazy okay apparently it is
here Valley of the
Kings okay this is down south wow
there's got to be a different Valley of
the
Kings anyway the point is this okay
let's not uh spend too much time
discovering the Valley of the Kings the
point is that uh the tomb of King Tuton
hamun was discovered sometime in the
1920s if I if my memory serves me right
1921 or 22 and the guy the archaeologist
who discovered this tomb was a guy
called Howard Carter he was most likely
British okay and
uh this narrative was created in the
media to sensationalize the discovery
that there was apparently some
inscription on the tomb which contained
a curse that anybody who anyone who
opens the tomb will be cursed and
whatnot and there was this
overall narrative that was already going
around that Egyptian mummies are cursed
and there are there are spells magical
spells or whatever on these mummies and
whoever opens mummies will meet an
untimely end that sort of narrative was
there so that is the so-called curse of
the Pharaohs but actually there was no
inscription such as that on the tomb and
uh so then the question is what happened
did people actually mysteriously die the
excav creers who Unearthed his tomb so
over over time people died some people
who were present over there died a year
or two later some people took longer
Howard Carter did not die until the
1930s so he's the main guy so why did he
not die if there was there was a curse
on the tomb so that's a great example of
the the fact that this story is
obviously not true yeah the guy the main
archaeologist who opened the tomb and
who was behind the entire archaeological
Expedition he lived for more than a
decade almost a decade and a half after
the excavation of the Tomb the guy who
financed the Expedition I think he died
a year or two later but he I don't think
he was there when the tomb was opened so
you know people eventually die so it
doesn't mean that it's connected to some
mysterious curse the the simplest
example the the starkest example is
Howard Carter who did not die for the
next 15 years after opening the tomb so
so
yeah Harel Agarwal says is the whole dat
of our civilization incorrect was it
done to match the timelines of the Arian
tourism Theory because the rig wther
cannot be 1. 5,000 BC come on what what
is that because of its detail and
explanation about the sarasti river it
must be be Beyond 5,000 BC at least what
are thoughts on this so yes I agree look
the it's a straightforward logical thing
the rigveda has copious numerous
references to the sarasti
River in which the river
is depicted and and and described as a
loudly Roaring River and the mother of
floods and much more okay the most
glorious of rivers the greatest of
rivers and so on so clearly it was the
largest river in the Indian subcontinent
at the time now we know where it flowed
and we have satellite imagery and all
that tells you where the river once
flowed it is now it no longer exists
sadly uh Saraswati G has left us maybe
because we stopped studying too much but
the river the Great River originated in
the Himalayas it was a in the north it
was a glacial meltwater fed River in the
South it was in as it moved southwards
it became a rainfed river at the time
the Indian rainy season was much much
more uh much heavier than what it is
today and the Great River drained out
into the r of cat somewhere over here
and if you look at uh you
know maps of the of the bottom of the
ocean you know of the topology of of the
under under sea so of the under sea
topology of the planet you will see the
drainage channel of the Saraswati in
Western India so it's still there it was
that massive so we know it was there and
now it no longer exists except in the
north where it does turn up during the
monsoon it is the it is now called the
gagar hakra river in the north somewhere
in the harana
region but yeah it it no longer flows
down south it because of the decline of
the Indian Monsoon it stopped existing
now the Riga mentions the Saraswati I
don't know how many dozens of times
maybe more than 100 times and it is
praised as the greatest of rivers and we
know that the Indian Monsoon started
declining slowly monotonically from
6,000 BC
onwards so 8,000 years ago the decline
of the river begins and we know that it
dried out in the southern part of India
around 1500 BC so the decline lasted
about 4 and a half thousand
years okay that's how long it took for
the river to to genuinely dry out it was
a very slow decline now in the ramayan
the sarasa is mentioned as a great River
in the Mahabharat the sarasti is is
mentioned as a river that's drying out
so there's a significant time difference
between the RAM and the
Mahabharat so the Mahabharat would have
happened closer to 1500 BC than to 6,000
BC and the Mahabharat in the ram the
ramayan would have happened closer to
6,000 BC than to 1500 BC in the
Mahabharat would have happened closer to
1500 BC than to 6,000 BC and the Riga
clearly predates the ramayan by the way
that is known that is the
chronology so what that tells you is
that the Riga was written closer to
6,000 BC and definitely before the
ramayan
so then this entire dating of the Arians
doing their P starting their picnic in
India in 1500 BC and then after a
century or two they Rite the rig wether
okay in in in Western India around 1300
BC that is such utter nonsense it is
deliberately constructed to force fit
certain dates on top of Indian history
which doesn't
work and then there are so so many other
problems with Indian history but the
dating of Indian history there are there
are multiple kings called Chandra Gupta
okay now we know that the Greeks the the
macedonians when they tried to invade
India
they um Alexander's invasion of India at
that time we had the nand Dynasty and
the Greeks then mentioned a ruler called
Sandra cotos which is one of the Chandra
Gupta rulers but how do you know it is
Chandra Gupta
Moria Beyond
conjecture in speculation we don't have
any hard evidence that the Chandra Gupta
that the Greeks referred to was Chandra
Gupta Moria and not some other Chandra
Gupta there were multiple Chandra guptas
just like there were multiple Vikram
Adas so these are the problems so it's
quite possible that our chronology is
fatally incorrect fatally flawed and
maybe so Mr V Arya has done significant
research on India's true
chronology and he has a whole different
chronology of India and I have done a
podcast with him maybe you want to check
it out if you're interested in this
topic so I think we need to revisit the
entire chronology of Indian history a
priority once again from
scratch uh I'm not very certain about
the date of the Buddha and mahavir and
Shankar aaria and the morian era it
could all be a thousand years or more
before what we believe it is because all
the whatever we believe is based on the
opinions of certain historians but there
is no hard evidence we do have Mor era
archaeological sites in relics and all
that but you cannot carbon date
stone you
can't right that's why it's very hard to
date a temple or date an archaeological
monument in a architectural Monument you
can't how do you date it how do you date
stone carbon dating carbon dating can
only be done on anything that contains
organic matter bones is a good example
bones you can carbon date bones and you
can even extract DNA if you're lucky and
so on but Stone doesn't contain organic
matter so how do you carbon date stone
yes sometimes you will find that under a
stone there are some there is something
left and maybe you it was organic matter
from that time that's something you can
assume but it doesn't prove anything so
I think the the point is the entire
chronology of Indian India's history
will have to be reexamined and a lot of
what we believe may be completely
mistaken and
incorrect sort of boria says is cultural
inferiority the reason for colonialism
or is it because of colonialism that
cultural inferiority has been created
among the ones is created among those
who were colonized Well India is a great
example India is full of mentally
colonized people I am one of them
because I am more comfortable using the
English language than native Indian
languages because of well because of the
way I was raised and the way I grew up
and the exposure and all that so I am
not in a minority most Indians are
mentally colonized to various degrees at
least I am proud of my history and my
ancestry ancestry is in all of us our
ancestry right in our history and our
great civilization I'm at least proud of
that many Indians are ashamed of that
they don't like it they they believe
that everything that came from outside
is better and India is all that so that
is the mental colonization that is the
inferiority complex lots of Indians have
lots of Indian have this inferiority
complex now the question that's asked
over here by sorup is a good question
this inferiority complex is it the
reason why you become colonized so do
you become colonized because you have an
inferiority complex or is colonization
the process that creates the inferiority
complex so let me explain you don't get
colonized because you have an
inferiority complex you get colonized
because you are militarily
inferior or tactically or ically
inferior that's how you come under
foreign occupation and then the
colonization starts colonization means
extraction of resources outside of your
country essentially beggaring you in the
process and enriching them at your
expense that's colonization that is
standard European Christian colonization
okay yeah it had a religious component
the religion was used to justify the
colonization because non-christians were
well they deserve to be enslaved and
then you so the process was that the
Pope would give a bull which would allow
these colonizers to go and grab any
nation and take over the land of any
nation whose people are not Christians
so you take the land you enslave the
people you extract everything out of
Valley out of the out of the place and
then as a Act of Mercy you give them the
choice that you convert or die or you
become slaves so then if you succeed in
converting these people then what
happens is that yeah you have done
something good so colonization was for a
good purpose yeah so that's the whole
justification
very yeah
so
uh so colonization happens if you
are militarily inferior or strategically
or tactically inferior or if you have
poor leadership despite being a strong
economy that's what that's or if you are
politically
disunited okay politically fragmented as
a as a as a nation or a civilization so
yeah India faced these problems mainly
because of a lack of political Unity
when the invasions happen the turkey
invasions and so on and then the
European Invasion Christian Invasion so
uh colonization is not because of
inferiority complex it is because of
these issues but then colonization once
the colonization happens what happens is
that your standards of living decline
your nation descends into abject poverty
and then they destroy your indigenous
education system they impose a foreign
language on you and then they teach you
that you are all inferior and you the
reason you are poor is because you
people are inferior not because we stole
all your wealth and destroyed all your
infrastructure and every all your
industries so the inferiority complex is
created after colonization by the
colonizers to justify colonization and
to prevent the natives who are being
oppressed and subjugated and destroyed
from rising up in Rebellion they will be
made to think that yeah we deserve it we
are so inferior the great white people
have come to save us we should try and
be more like them that's how it
goes J rata says why did any Indian
trust a political party the Inc
established by a British person Alan
Hume how can an Indian rely on it for
getting Independence where were were
there any wise men in India at the time
of Independence who knew the reality of
the Congress and opposed it well Mr
subash Chandra BOS he was no longer a
congressman Mr Gandhi was no longer a
congressman in 1946 1947 1948 I think Mr
Gandhi resigned from the primary
membersip of the of the congress party
in the 1930s some sometime in the 1930s
was it 1934 36 somewhere around that
time maybe before that now the main
question is why did Indians trust a
political party that was created by the
British so first of all why did the
British create this party the British
were aware that Indians had this desire
for independence from for freedom from
these foreign occupiers and oppressors
1857 was a great example of what would
have happened you know the British faced
this tremendous outpouring of anger the
whole nation went to war against them
and they somehow were able to suppress
this and in 1857 they destroyed every
single royal family that stood against
them wiped them out and then put puppets
in their
place puppets in their place okay then
and those puppets their descendants
still I mean still are recognized as
so-called whatever yeah so
so what the British did what Alan Hume
this guy did is that he created a
political party the Indian National
Congress or whatever it was called the
day those days I think it was called
that and this political
party the objective was that it will
become the movement that will channel
the energy of the Indian independence
movement and it will be channeled in the
right ways no violence no no real
opposition of the British all the
leaders of the of this movement should
be British educated English educated
Anglo files who whose first language is
English more than any native
language most of them should have been
educated in England have a degree from
England and so on and that's what you
see in everyone except for Mr Patel and
Mr Patel was a DieHard loyalist of Mr
Gandhi who was a British educated
lawyer okay so that was the purpose of
the of this political party to take the
to to first of all it would be
positioned as the only legitimate Avenue
for the Indian independence movement
anybody who did who fought for Indian
independence outside of this political
party would be labeled as an
extremist I mean I believe they called
bhagat Singh an extremist and a
terrorist right so anybody who was not
part of the Indian movement Independence
Movement through this party was either
an extremist or a terrorist and they
were treated horribly they were all
hanged and tortured and whatnot
and so that was it so the objective was
to make it appear to Indians that there
is a political party that that is taking
care of our aspirations you know a
completely artificial non-g Grassroots
political
party can you think of any more recent
political party like that I'm I'm just
saying I'm not saying
anything so so it was a fake fake
Freedom Movement that that was designed
to delay Independence for India okay
that's what it was now in those days
there was no social media in those days
the entire press was controlled by the
British so you could not write anything
that was too critical of the British in
that you could you know sometimes
pretend to
be slightly anti-british but not too
much so the entire press was
controlled with an iron fist by the
British there was no TV the radio still
wasn't there I believe maybe it was
there but it was very rudimentary in
most Indians for most Indians R Radio
was as expensive as as buying most
Indians could not afford it there was no
electricity in in India by the way those
days so nobody knew about radio you
would have one radio in every city
mediumsized city no radios in villages
obviously there was no TV there was no
internet there was no GE there was no
vone there was
nothing so the narrative could be
controlled you could spread any
narrative you want wanted you could say
through the media and whatnot that this
is the legitimate political party that
will achieve independence for India
whenever India deserves it and so on so
that's how it was done so the wise I'm
I'm sure there were wise people who
could see through it but who knew them
they would never be allowed to come up
they would be marginalized and if they
spoke too much they would be taken care
of that's the kind of India it was it
was not a free India it was India under
foreign occupation worse than the Nazis
these anglos were worse than the Nazis
by the
way maybe but you don't know it you
don't realize it because your text books
exall their their virtues to the High
Heavens so yeah so that's the whole deal
that's why Indians trust at political
parties and Indians are still so gulal
even today that despite the age of
social media despite all the facts being
there in front of you many Indians still
vote for
certain fake political uh parties that
were
that serve other nations agenda and they
still believe utter nonsense and and
lies and propaganda by certain YouTubers
and whatnot so what can I say even today
Indians haven't grown up many not all
some of you are very wise those who
watch me thank
you okay madavan VOD says how did so
much linguistic diversity developed in
Papa new Guin more than a thousand
languages on both sides of the Island
and why do we not find such diversity in
India uh go good interesting question
let's go to the map where is Papa new
guine it is to the east of India so we
go east east east east east east east
east and north of Australia you have
papan Nini so and then there is the the
it is there's a straight line over here
and to the West you have Indonesian
administr territory and to the east you
have the nation of Papa New Guinea but
the entire island is the Homeland of the
papuan people papuan people okay it's a
very large island very rich in natural
resources etc etc and like uh venod says
more than a thousand languages are
spoken on the island so if you look at
the topography and all that of the
island you'll see that there are
mountain
ranges so there's a mountain range over
here if you go to the three dimensional
view it's not really mountains it's
Hills you have Hills and you have fall
forests it's a completely Green
Island there are very few actual cities
the only city of any kind of any size in
in the east of the island is Port morby
which itself is kind of an glorified
Village okay and
uh they're all uh today in the East
converted to Christianity as far as I
know most of them some of them who are
still isolated may have their own
whatever culture they have so the deal
is this this these people the papuan
people are well what one would call less
developed people they all lived in the
form of isolated tribes isolated from
each other for centuries sometimes in
various parts of the island small tribes
100 or two maybe 200 some of them would
be 50 strong some of them could be
larger so they never had kingdoms they
never had Empires they never had
civilization the way we know
civilization they all lived in tribal
groups isolated in remote parts of the
island it's a very large island the
population density is very low so
because of these reasons so many
different languages evolved
independently in isolation from each
other even though the people are
genetically very alike but they you keep
people up two tribal groups apart for
200 years they're going to speak
languages that are that are that become
Divergent over time so that's the deal
when it comes to India India is a whole
different kind of thing
India uh India first of all we know the
history of India very large population
even 5,000 years ago India had a
population of about 5 million the
largest population density in the world
even during the uh Indus harapan sarasti
Sindu phase of our history and all and
something about Indians we were
well well developed I guess we had
uh we had
cities we had Urban Development even
five six thousand years ago during the
sarasa Sindu phase so we are a different
culture and different civilization the
pop on have a whole different history
and we also have so many different
dialects I mean if you go to various
parts of India you have various language
families but every city has a every
district has a slightly different way of
speaking whatever language they speak
and all so you can see something like
that in India also but India was much
more interconnected even 5,000 years ago
India was interconnected with highways
and Roads and all that the way paper was
not so there was constant exchange
interchange of of uh language of culture
of customs of traditions of stories of
people of goods services so on so forth
across India which is why India evolved
as a sing is a single civilization
despite having lots of different
dialects and languages and lots of
different local customs
okay lak bhak says I follow you since
your first post on chingis Khan thank
you so much that's that's been a while I
want to ask you about King BGE who was
King
BJ King BJ so King BJ was Raja BJ we
talk about Raja B he was a very
significant King in the first half he
ruled the region of present day madha
Pradesh in the first half of the the
11th century so it's uh 1, ad to 150 ad
around that time okay the exact dates
man maybe slightly off but he ruled
Central India mostly the region of
President the madh Pradesh about a
thousand or so years ago he was a very
prominent King of the permar dynasty
rajput Dynasty okay the permar and he is
remembered for his tremendous
contributions to culture to literature
architecture and uh his Reign is
considered to be a golden age for his
kingdom and for that entire region that
entire part of India and he was very
strong militarily he conducted
multiple campaigns successful campaigns
to expand and consolidate his kingdom
his administration was very effective
very effective governance uh people had
high levels of prosperity very good
living standards he constructed many
temples magnificent temples in his
kingdom the bwar temple in bjur bjur is
named after Raja boj obviously so the
bwar temple is a great example it is
dedicated dedicated to Lord Shiva um uh
what El he founded the city of bjur
which is which was his Capital then he
established the BJ Shala center of
learning also a temple of goddess
Saraswati well B Shala is yeah it's
under a cloud right now whatever is left
of it uh but he constructed that he he
uh was a patron of many scholars and
Poets and artists and this brought about
uh a Renaissance kind of environment
very vibrant cultural environment it is
said that he was a scholar who uh wrote
books on on various subjects like uh
poetry philosophy astronomy and all that
and so overall a great king he is
remembered as one could say an ideal
King you know a very just very wise King
an ideal King a patron of all everything
that is good so uh he left a very
lasting impact on India's culture and
history and that's why he is remembered
with great fondness today so that is
Raja BJ in
brief Priyanka tanija says how do
Nations decide on their capital city
what factors do they
consider um
look usually cap cities
come it's not like you you are the king
of a country and then you sit down and
and think to yourself okay I need a
capital so let me take a look at all the
good all the cities in the country on in
my kingdom and which of these cities is
ideally suited for being a capital it's
not like that it doesn't happen like
that what typically happens is that a
new Dynasty comes up in some part of the
country let's take a look at India okay
this is India so some Dynasty emerged
emerges from somewhere okay for
example uh the Moria
Dynasty emerged from
patliputra and so patliputra became the
capital of the Moria Dynasty then the
Gupta dynasty also emerged from the same
city of patliputra so the so patliputra
because it was the seat of the early
Gupta dynasty it remained the capital
now when it comes to somebody like uh
keska who had a much larger Empire uh he
had two capitals one was I believe
matura was it and the other was purpur
pavati which is present day pesha where
there is nothing left of the original
culture so I
think Capital Cities become capitals
because of various circumstances of
History not because they are the ideal
city ideal city to be a capital when it
comes to let's say a nation like tur
turkey well historically the most
prominent city was Constantinople now
called Istanbul right so it was the seat
of the Ottoman Sultans the kifs but when
uh Mustafa kamalat deposed I mean he
abolished the the the the the the
caliphate the Ottoman Empire and he
fought the Turkish war of independence
which happened before the abolition of
the caliphate he chose a new capital for
himself for the nation anara in the
middle of
Anatolia so yeah it was a smart choice a
city which was at the time kind of in
the middle of nowhere Anatolia was a
very dry desolate it still is kind of
region but he chose a city here and
maybe it was a good choice you know a
city in the middle of the nation kind of
in the middle of the nation as opposed
to being on the fringes of the
nation uh when it comes to Iran its
historical Capital was parur pis which
is is destroyed and now it is tan I
don't remember why how tan became the
capital China it's always been China has
had multiple capitals by the way Beijing
was not always the capital of China it
had other cities Xian was a capital and
other other cities are also capitals of
China
so typically a capital city becomes a
capital because it it was the original
seat of a small Dynasty that went on to
rule the whole country but uh when it
comes to India maybe it's time to think
of a new capital city so our capital
city dilika New Deli DHI it's an ancient
city very ancient city it is K PR Indra
prast of the Pand era of the Mahabharat
era it was also the capital of uh praj
Chan and Raja hu Vikram
vikramaditya the last Hindu king of
India of all of all of India of Delhi at
least and so on but we have had various
capitals we've had patliputra we've had
uh matura wherever it
is we yeah matura is over here which
other cities were capitals of
India
uh pesha yes during during kanishka's
time and so on so if you look at the map
of India the ideal place for having a
capital city is probably somewhere in
madhya Pradesh
you know the heart the heart of India
currently the city of Delhi the current
capital of Delhi it's barely about
what it's barely 300 400 kilometers from
Chinese occupied Tibet which is not a
very good thing so ideally we should
have a capital maybe in madha Pradesh or
maybe somewhere further
south but yeah let's see if that ever
happens
okay happy faces 228 says I don't
understand how people can force
forcefully be converted from one
religion to another Invaders can destroy
temples but how can they decide whom
people
worship okay yeah once the Invaders are
gone people will again switch their
religion please explain that's an
interesting phenomenon you're referring
to okay let's take the let's take one of
the examples okay the uh occupation of
Goa by the Portuguese so let's once
again go to the map as as we know the
Portuguese ruled Goa they occupied Gua
for quite some time until the 1960s or
something when we threw them out
eventually so when they took over this
region the Portuguese the Portuguese
were the most brutal of the Christian
Invaders and occupiers of India European
Christian OCC occupi of India the most
brutal so this fellow
Xavier okay who is considered a saint
today he ordered an inquisition in Goa
so when the Portuguese took possession
of this of this region they destroyed
all the Hindu temples and lots of people
had to take the vgas and the shivlings
ETC and go down south and escape with
those things and all of those temples
are either in Ruins or they have been
replaced by churches and then they
forcibly converted people the people who
lived in these regions and those who
secretly practice Hinduism despite being
officially converted they were executed
they were tortured they were burned
alive there there was an Inquisition and
all kinds of horrific cruel atrocities
so people initially resisted they tried
to secretly practice Hinduism their
ancestral Faith but they were brutally
suppressed repressed and uh all kinds of
horrific atrocities were done there was
this pillar somewhere in Goa where
hundreds of hands would cut off hands
chopped off hands would be would be uh
displayed the hands of those who were
practicing Hinduism in secret so through
this Relentless brutality the Portuguese
were able to convert the majority of the
the people of Goa to Christianity by
complete Force forcefully okay but if
you go go to Goa today the
people many people in go are more
Portuguese than the Portuguese today
okay so that's how it happens so you
convert them and then you teach them the
language and the customs and then your
your education system is also religious
in nature which means that the children
are Indo indoctrinated in this religion
and this belief from their very first
days from the days when they can first
start speaking and then this
brainwashing continues generation after
generation and after a few Generations
they are more Portuguese than the
Portuguese despite what what was done to
their
ancestors that's just one example there
are other religions also that do this so
that's how it happens so you capture the
education system you capture the
religious system you capture all the
books okay you you gain complete control
over the entire narrative and then you
can make people believe whatever they
want whatever you want and I I know for
a fact that most of these descendants of
these people in Goa they know what
happened to their ancestors but they
okay with it which is I don't know what
sort of inferiority complex that is but
it is what it is Indians are famous for
their inferiority
complex okay Moody Kish says the recent
excavations in vadnagar Gujarat have
revealed the presence of civilized
metropolitan cities in the post harapan
f phase does this discovery de debunk
the so-called dark post dark phase in
Post harapan history okay what is this
so-called dark phase so you know the
sarasvati Hindu phase of Indian history
the so-called harapan civilization or
India indust Valley Civilization
uh mainstream historians will tell you
in most of your textbooks will tell you
that there was this great civilization
there which somehow mysteriously
vanished probably because the so-called
invading Arians came and Destro it and
then there was a thousand years of
complete darkness in which there was no
civilized activity because the AR Arians
were still Nomads and they were still
getting used to civilized
life and that's the narrative that you
have okay so apparently these great
cities M Hara rakari K Kali Kali bangan
and so on and so forth all of these
suddenly were abandoned because of the
invasion or the migration of of the
aians and everything was destroyed and
and then the civilization disappears
truth the truth is that the civilization
never disappeared what happened was that
there was a climate change event in
India which lasted centuries and
centuries and there was also a period of
extended drought which kind of
exacerbated the migration away from
these cities and we know that the Great
River sarasti dried out because of
climate change because of the decline in
the Indian rainy season the monsoon over
several thousand years so there was this
climate change which necessitated the
moving away of people from these big
cities for a viy of reasons and they
moved to other parts of India some of
them went westwards where is the map
here's the map so then you you had
various places even west of the Saras
Hindu region sub Hindu region where
these people went and uh settled but
most of them went eastwards in in into
various parts various parts of the
Indian subcontinent some of them went
West some of them went North but most of
them went eastwards in towards more
fertile uh and plentiful paths of the
Indian subcontinent that's what happened
so this was a process that took about a
thousand years of the migration of the
the the people of these regions of these
great cities to other parts of India it
was a slow process of a thousand years
and the cities gradually fell into
disuse and the people created they built
new cities
elsewhere so the more you excavate the
more you will discover this and these
new excavations in Wagar and other
places have demon strated that there was
no dark period or dark phase it was a
gradual migration of people to other
parts of India that's that's all it was
and the there are thousands of sarasa
Hindu era cities and archaeological
sites thousands of them that that have
never been touched
archaeologically that that have never
been examined so that needs to happen
then we will actually know what really
happened okay Sor boria says what is
thaism how when was it start started was
it influenced by bat as it seems it
philos as it seems philosophically
similar to Indian dharmic thoughts like
Hinduism Buddhism
jism and so on
thaism what was thaism was also called
DSM right it's a philosophical and
religious tradition from China it
originated in China maybe about 2,000 or
so years ago China is about 3,000 years
old as a civilization maybe three and a
half thousand years old so thaism
originated about 2,000 years
ago uh in China and ta means the path
the right way the way so the teachings
of taism are are about the right way of
living the right path it's about you
have to live in harmony with t which is
the
fundamental principle that underlies and
harmonizes and uh unifies the universe
so it's about living in harmony with th
that's what it is and there are these
principles like yin and yang the balance
of this and that that's what taism is
about it is kind of an atheistic system
there is no Divinity or or God in thaism
Hinduism is very different Hindu Dharma
bodha Dharma J Dharma the whatever
dharmic paths we have they are very
different there's a wide range of
beliefs the concept of Brahman the
Ultimate Reality the the the concept of
Karma birth
rebirth uh Dharma Moka all these things
devotion biti knowledge Gana righteous
action all of these are part of Hinduism
also Buddhism Buddhism you have the four
noble truths and the eight Eightfold
Path to attain nirvan Enlightenment
which is also there in Hinduism and so
on so that is Buddhism Hinduism taism is
about the thaism also has meditation it
has ta taii Kong various rituals aimed
at harmonizing you with the TA in
achieving spiritual balance and all that
Hinduism we also have meditation we have
various kinds of meditation we have yoga
we have Puja we have t pilgrimages
Buddhism also has very similar things so
there are certain similarities in all
but in the case of
thaism there is no Divinity there is no
God some taist will will worship certain
deities and Spirits like ancestor
worship nature worship some of them will
do it but most of them do not do it
Hinduism is polytheistic vast panthe of
gods Buddhism is kind of
non-theistic but when it comes to
Mahayana Buddhism they also have
Buddhist atas and various divinities so
overall thaism is more of an atheistic
system it it is all about balance and
Harmony and the the right path ta it's
about Kong and taii and meditation so
some in some ways it is kind of similar
to Indian practices but in some ways it
is quite different philosophically also
some similarities and some
differences all right
okay rodrit says why didn't the USA ever
see a military kud and sabir Kazi says
why is the US so efficient effective and
consistent with policies even though
it's a democracy what should India learn
from the
US is the US a democracy we know India
is a democracy we have thousands of
political parties every election you
have hundreds of political parties
standing vying for for the seats in
whatever whe it's a municipal election
or or district election or state
election or or general election Central
election you have thousands of political
parties it's it's a complete chaotic
messy Festival of democracy that is
Indian democracy that is genuine
democracy there are parties for
everything every single minority
majority every religion every religious
denomination everybody has a political
party of their own every region has it
multiple political parties that is
genuine Dem Ry in the
US you have two political parties you
have more but those don't
matter if you look at the the
Congress if you look at the House of
Representatives if you look at the
various uh representative houses of
various states in the US there's only
representation of two political parties
the Democrats and the Republicans so the
US even though it calls itself a
democracy is actually a two-party system
a two- party state which is one step
above a one party State like China and
North Korea and when it comes to these
two parties the the Democrats and the
the Republicans they have the same
foreign policy and they're all in bed
with the with the oligarchs the military
industrial complex and various
billionaires and whatnot so the US is an
autocracy masquerading it's a it's a
democracy it's a police state the US is
a police state there are so many cops
everywhere you go to New York City and
just open your eyes for a change and
look around and see how many cops you'll
see and I guarantee this whether it's
New York City whether it's San Francisco
whether it's Los Angeles or whichever
big city in the US you take those cops
away for half an hour there's going to
be riots on the streets so the US is a
police state it's a militaristic state
everybody has guns there are more guns
than people in the US and it has just
two political parties which have the
same foreign policy so it's essentially
an autocracy a military police state
masquerading is a democracy that's why
it's so effective consistent with policy
and all that and that's why it's
actually an
Empire masquerading is a superpower
right and that's why there's no K
because it is so tightly controlled so
there you have it so what can India
learn from the US learn hypocrisy learn
how to fool the
world yeah it's it's a it's a good skill
to
have herel agrawal says please discuss
the history of Central Asia in brief
like the truckers the kushanas the Huns
and the turkic invasions how they
started and when they started in the
region okay Central Asia where's Central
Asia where's the
map so we know where India is
historically the Indian subcontinent was
I mean India was larger Afghanistan and
Pakistan were part of India India's
borders during the time of sh chingis
Khan the border of Afghanistan with
Tajikistan that was the border of India
with Central Asia
okay um
now Central Asia for the longest time
for about 2,000 years or so was called
skiya so you had these indo-iranian
people in this region who were look you
there are multiple there are records of
multiple waves of migration out of India
in the past 10,000 years starting with
the battle of the 10 Kings so there were
lots of Indian origin kingdoms thousands
of years in the past in the Central
Asian region and they eventually went
their own way and developed their own
customs and rituals and language and
whatnot and the skians were these people
the SK they were nomadic people who
ruled this entire vast step the Central
Asian region and they were
polytheistic people who worshiped the
son and other gods and they spoke what
is today classified as an Iranian
language I would say Indo Iranian or
whatever and they reinvaded India and
reconquered India about 2,000 or so
years ago and they very harmoniously
assimilated with the Indian population
today nobody knows who's a descendant of
skians because well they were
genetically very similar to Indians and
cult Cally and linguistically also very
similar to Indians so there was a very
harmonious assimilation of the skians
with the Indians about 2,000 years ago
and the various skan dynasties ruled
India for until about 14500 years ago
including the northern satraps and the
Western mahak shatas and so on so that
is the skians and if you look at uh the
Caucasus region today well people there
also have skan ancestry there are lots
of people all across Central Asia and
Eastern Europe Etc who have skan
ancestry uh this region the the European
part of uh turkey was historically
called
th and th and all this Bulgaria Romania
Etc that was also regions ruled by
skians even Ukraine the the the much of
Ukraine all the way up to present day
Zang where you had the kushan so where
also you could say the eastern most
skians so that is about the skians uh
the kushans were like like I said you
can consider them them to be the eastern
most skians they are probably Clos
closely related to the tarim river
basing people the tarim river mummy
people who look European in nature but
if you look at their culture it was very
Indian and if you look at the genetics
it is R1 A1A among the tarim river
mummies so even though they look kind of
European with blonde hair and and red
hair and all that
genetically they
were yeah interesting and the kushans
were probably closely related to the
tarim River Basin people and the kushans
also ruled India for a few centuries and
they also assimilated very harmoniously
with the Indian population which means
that they were culturally genetically
quite alike quite very much like the
Indians and kishka was one of our
greatest Emperors who who did more for
spreading Indian culture worldwide than
almost anybody else so that is the
kushans and the Huns were these tribal
nomadic people who emerged out of the
region of present day Mongolia more or
less and then they defeated the skians
at various points in time and they ruled
over Central Asia sometime in the past
uh 16 1700 years and they were the the
Huns eventually were the ancestors of
the Turks as well as the Mongols even
today the Mongolian word for human being
is who
who which kind of comes from H I think
it's hu
hu uh and so on and the turkic invasions
started in this region with the hunnik
invasions and the Huns were trying to
invade India at the same time when they
were trying to invade Rome as well so
they can see how far apart they were how
how far wide widely they were spread out
the Huns very powerful nomadic
confederations Raiders and tribes people
and they tried tried to invade India
during the Gupta era and other Emperors
kand Gupta repelled wave after wave
after wave of honic invasion which
depleted his Treasury and his financial
resources eventually the Gupta Empire
declined and the HS were able to conquer
parts of India and the H also assulated
very harmoniously with the Indian
population so there you have it shakas
kushans as well as hun and the turkic
people were the descendants of the Hons
and they eventually adopted a foreign
religion religion of the Arabs
Islam
okay aniket says Universe 25 experiment
the universe 25 experiment was this uh
experiment with rats I believe it was
conducted by an
American researcher in the 1960s 1970s
it was about uh the effect of population
density on behavior of rats of rat
communities
so what happens when you have a rat
community in a closed environment very
good environment with abundant unlimited
food and every resource but what happens
when there is a growth in the population
what happens when there is
overpopulation how does it affect the
behavior and the social structures of
these animal rat communities okay so
there was this enclosed habitat a large
enclosed habitat with four rooms or
something it was called universe 25 and
it had mice or rats I think mice and uh
these mice were provided unlimited food
unlimited water nesting materials
whatever other resources mice need to
thrive so initially a population of I
think 25
mice I don't know how many initially a
small population was introduced in this
habitat okay they were all healthy they
were all disease free they were all
pretty happy mice and the conditions
were very ideal for them to prosper and
Thrive and be happy ample space ample
resources so what this did is that it
caused rapid population growth so so
there is rapid population growth and
there is prosperity because everything
is there rat mice populations double
about every 50 days or so 50 60 days the
mice population doubles so uh initially
they all exhibited normal social
behaviors they formed territories they
form social groupings they raised their
young successfully but then what happens
is that the population kept on Rising
the population density kept on Rising
and then you saw signs of stress and
discomfort and then the behavior started
changing the social hierarchies that are
inherent in every society human or
animal these social hierarchy started
changing and they started breaking down
and there were there was a collapse of
social structures and there was
aggressive there was there was collapse
of normal behavioral patterns aggressive
behaviors started dominating antisocial
behaviors started dominating violence
cannibalism infanticide infant mortality
went through the roof the mice okay more
than 90% of infant started dying because
the mice became withdrawn isolated they
refused to engage in normal activities
they refused to mate they refused to
build nests and all kinds of weirdness
you saw and then the birth rate started
plummeting precipitously and the
population started declining mortality
rates went up went to the roof because
of neg of infants and violence among all
these uh various rat mice so despite
having abundant resources abundant food
abundant water the population started
declining eventually the population
collapsed and almost went
extinct so what this tells you is that
it's not enough to be
prosperous okay and and this is
something that that applies even to
human societies okay it is kind of
speculative obviously
but the overcrowding and social the
overcrowding was a very big factor in
this matter despite having abundant food
AB abundant water abundant resources
whatever you want there was overcrowding
and there was they were all confined in
this city-like environment they could
not go out of that okay and there was
the absence of any danger there were no
Predators there were no challenges so
they all became complacent and it was
very unnatural
uh it was a very unnatural situation to
be in so when you have overpopulation
when you have high density living
conditions even if you have Prosperity
even if you have abundant
resources your social structures break
down your behavior breaks down there is
stress there is mental health problems
there is the breakdown of social order
there is a decline in uh birth rates
there is an increase in mortality and so
on so this could be relevant to humans
also so it's it's a it's a very you
could say significant it's a
groundbreaking experiment that was
conducted in the 1960s or 70s about
social psychology about the potential
consequences of
overpopulation and one could say that
there is some applicability of this to
human beings as well so that's the
universe 25
experiment okay two questions
rodit says Israel reestablished the
Hebrew language after the establishment
of Israel why didn't we India
reestablish Sanskrit as our official
language instead of English after our
independence as it would have helped us
solve our language problems and and
helped us understand our ancient
religious philosophical spiritual
civilizational texts and connect with
our own culture even more do you think
there is any way to correct this mistake
even now in Gat 3 ing says you earlier
said the s Sanskrit should be made the
official language of India and English
should be eliminated eliminated
completely you've given the example of
China and France that don't use English
and they're still doing well but French
and Chinese are the official language at
many International institutions but
India doesn't have that facility so in
that way in what way making Sanskrit the
national language will affect India's
performance at the global stage you see
French was not
always an official language in various
International institutions Chinese was
not always an official language in many
International institutions this happened
because the stature and relevance of
these nations
grew India until the last 5 10 years has
been an irrelevant
Nation so that's why nobody uses any
Indian language anywhere nobody wants to
learn Hindi or any Indian language when
your nation starts becoming genuinely
internationally relevant everybody will
start paying attention to you and giving
importance to your culture in your
language so that's how French became
established as the official language in
many International institutions that's
how the same thing happened to Chinese
Arabic and so on and how did English
become the international
language in 1800 French was more of an
international language than English how
did it happen through
imperialism and through the British
Empire so to make your language accepted
globally you have to spread your Ro
Roots you have to spread your power
projection abilities and you have to
spread your you to increase your
relevance you have to become a genuinely
relevant Nation then this happens but
you have to first have some
self-confidence that we will use our own
language as the official language that's
what you need to do you to start that
way backwards you don't say we will
first become relevant then we'll bring
in Sanskrit you start by becoming more
confident in yourself by having some
self- resect and having your own
civilization language the is the
official national language and then you
grow grow grow and everybody if they
want to interact with you will have to
learn your language and because you're
so powerful and now now so well
respected everybody will make your
language one of their official languages
that's how it
works
okay so making sunkit the national
language will make India
more will
will engender self-respect among Indians
it will also make people in respect
India more right now we are speaking a
foreign language people laugh at us
behind our backs you may not realize it
okay so now that's the deal now about
Hebrew and why didn't we reestablish
srit because our leaders were all
mentally colonized losers most of them
not all most of them so-called leaders
so-called founding fathers I mean there
was some debate of making Sanskrit the
national language but they chose no
Hindi hog Hindi for some
reason and uh yeah English is also still
one of the official languages and people
like me can speak English better than
any native language which is sad right
uh so yes I think there's still a way to
correct this mistake you can correct the
whole thing in 20 years you know
introduce the education in the education
system and make it the official language
you start with class zero
kindergarten what is it called Nursery
first year you introduce Nursery the
official language and Sanskrit is not
like a foreign language that you to
learn a foreign language first and all
that Sanskrit is part of our blood any
Indian language has 50 60% Sanskrit
vocabulary anyway so introducing srit is
not going to traumatize the kids at all
it's going to actually make them more
intelligent and brighter and more
connected to the roots so introduce it
one year at a time first at the nursery
level then Junior kg senior kg then
first standard second stand and in 20
years you've you've made the whole
education education system sunkit
compliant and that's how we do it and it
will take a leader of some fortitude
to do this because there's a lot of uh
opposition to Sanskrit within India
these days especially when it comes to
various Nos and institutions that are
connected to outside Financial funds and
the various uh conversion factories and
missionary supported organizations and
all that in India and various Third Rate
Regional for political parties that want
to create divisions in India for their
own political benefits I'm not naming
anybody but I'm just saying so because
of all these reasons there's a lot of
oppos position to Sanskrit in India in
various parts of India but it is our
civilization language it's been the only
civilization language of India at least
10,000 years and we have to bring it
back I think it can be done if we have a
leadership that has a bit of fortitude
and maybe at the right time okay
yeah okay uh off p425 says I'm 15 years
old my height is 5.5t I want to be 6
feet tall suggest me exercises and for
it and San bishwas says I'm currently
5'8 height at the age of 19 I want to
increase my height by 4 cm six 6 feet
yeah as most of my peers are taller than
me should I go should I undergo limb
lengthening
surgery okay look first of all the first
question I'm 15 I want to be six feet
tall I'm 5.5 feet so you got what five
seven seven inches to go suggest
exercising diet I would suggest a very
clean diet lots of vegetables and I
don't know
15 100 120 grams of protein per day
depending on whether you're vegetarian
or nonvegetarian you would choose
various sources if you are a vegetarian
paneer is a great source paneer is a
cottage cheese it contains protein and a
good amount of fat and that would also
be a good fuel source for you if you
don't eat P then you can go for various
pulses which come with a lot of
carbohydrates but okay that's that's
what vegetarians have to deal with if
you're non-vegetarian then we have
various uh meat-based sources animal
based sources for protein so you need to
eat lots of vegetables and a good amount
of protein every day that's number one
that's diet exercises go to the track
Run Track and Field running jumping
throwing and contact
Sports Mar martial arts boxing or
something like kabadi or something and
also if you have the time go to gym and
lift heavy weights start with light
please otherwise you'll get injured so
that's what you do you need to be active
I think the best activity for for
increasing your height is track and
field Athletics because that brings out
your genetics and it gives your genetic
uh potential it it brings out your full
genetic potential running and jumping
essentially that's what the human be
body is designed to
do now to Sayan bishwas should I undergo
limb lengthening surgery well I would
not recommend it I would not recommend
doing anything unnatural because at the
end of the day how does it matter
whether you whatever your height is 58
is not
bad it's okay
look everybody is dealt a certain set of
cards your genetic Lottery your the
whatever gifts the gods have given you
you know it is said that when before you
are born you choose all your attributes
before you before you before you take
birth that's what some people say my
point is this at the end of the day what
matters in life is what you what you
make of life not how how tall it is how
tall you are and how you
look of course that that gives you some
pleasure and all that but at the end of
the day what you achieve in life and
what you contribute to society and what
impact you have is more important than
what than how many inches tall you are
feet and inches okay so I would say I
would I would I would really not advise
you to undergo limb lengthening surgery
it's pretty traumatic they first break
your bones and then they lengthen it and
you will spend at least 6 months in a
wheelchair it's horrific why why would
you want to put yourself through the
torture okay if you if you have any
issues with with how you look I would
say 58 is not bad but I will recommend
clean up your diet and go to gym and
lift weights do it for the next two
years and you will see a total
transformation in your body that's what
I would say so I would not recommend
limb lengthening surgery surgery by any
means but at the end of the day it's
your choice because you are you're the
person who gets to decide what to do
life okay do we have any other questions
left I think we are done we are done so
now what we do is I will take a few
questions from the live chat I know many
of you are there on the live chat so
please ask me some questions I'll take
maybe three or four questions from the
live chat before we wrap
up okay crew wit says skians genetic
similarity lower than 10% with Iranian
at the time how can skians be Iranian
with very low genetic Connection in very
different culture you know you ask
Linguistics evident linguist linguistic
experts they will they will say that
skan is classified as an Iranian
language linguistic is linguistics is a
pseudo science it should be very
scientific it should be based on
scientific rules the
way we had the rules of Panini for
Sanskrit those are proper scientific and
algorithmic and logical rules today
Linguistics is a joke so they will come
up with any story to link something with
something skians are
Iranians um genetically skians uh I have
not really seen studies of late what the
what genetically they're like skians
were genetically very diverse because
they they ruled over such a vast area of
Central Asia they would have some
mongolic genes some honik genes some
European is genes definitely Indian
subcontinental genes some Iranian genes
and some whatever else very diverse
population but the original skians the
ones who lived about let's say 4,000
5,000 years before today I would like to
see their genetic studies that would be
more interesting so uh yeah so today
people can claim any nonsense you know
even genetic studies are kind of dodgy
these days I mean they will draw
conclusions about about India's genetic
history based on genetic samples taken
from outside the outside the country
outside the subcontinent so there's all
kinds of nonsense going on these days
I'm I'm kind of become I've kind of
become disinterested interested in this
topic uh I used
to keep track of what was happening Visa
the Arian Invasion migration tourism
picnic thing but these days I'm not
looking looking into it but overall yeah
I would say that they claim that skians
are Iranian the best I would say is that
skians are Indo Iranian but actually
they are of subcontinental origin uh
that's what I would
say Okay Rohit B says you mentioned Kush
shakers assimilated assimilated with
quotes in the society with Indian
society and became a part of Indian
culture how do you think this happened
considering they were Invaders and like
abrahamic Invaders think about it when
the
morian when the morian Empire expanded
they were also
Invaders right they conquered various
parts of Western India Southern India
Northern India the morans were also
Invaders what happened did anything
happen did anything happen nothing
happened it's the these regions simply
came under a new Administration new king
and They carried on with their lives the
tax taxation structure won't change much
lifestyle won't change much no major
change similarly when the kushans and
the shakas the shakas first came and
conquered India they would have fought
with the various armies of various
Indian Kings defeated them and then
established their Kingdom and then
nothing much
changes nothing much changes for the
Indian population and then you would
have some skians would come and settle
down in various parts of India
maybe uh and and that also would have
been reasonably harmonious because they
had similar language and similar Customs
polye polythetic culture like you say
not abrahamic Invaders so they they did
not attempt to impose a foreign ideology
or religion or culture on the natives
instead they just simply assimilated
means I will take some of your culture
maybe you can take some of mine if you
choose to but yeah let's live in peace
that's how it how it happened
unfortunately we have no texts left from
those days everything was burned in the
destruction of the great University so
we don't know how what exactly happened
I am sure some people would have written
about it how these events happened but
we've lost it but we know they
assimilated because the genetics all
mixed
up
okay blood Monger says is the US going
to apply sanctions on India due to the
recent news of India and Iran's deal on
the chabahar port or is it just an
intimidation tactic I think they will
not impose any sanctions or if they
impose some sanctions it could be on
some small um on some limited uh
commercial interests and very limited
sanctions but yeah it's a symbolic
threat that we are bigger than you we
are stronger than you we can do whatever
the hell we want to you if we choose to
remember that we have destroyed Iran we
have destroyed other nations just
through sanctions and we could do the
same thing to you so you better behave
it's it's it's it's an arm twisting
tactic it's an intimidation tactic it's
a bullying tactic so I don't think
they're actually going to impose any
sanctions if they do impose sanctions
those will not be very serious sanctions
there'll be limited sanctions not on the
whole country but it's it's it's a
tactic of intimidation bullying and arm
twisting that's what it
is all right let us take maybe one more
question chinki says is carnivore diet
good for Indians carnivore diet means
you eat only meat um I don't know
um I think there are people in the west
who say that who sing praises of the car
carnivore diet I think Joe Rogan has
gone carnivore at times I believe that
this guy Peterson Jordan Peterson eats
only beef how nice how nice in his
daughter too apparently look to each
their own I would say I don't know if
carore diet is good for Indians I don't
think it's we are genetically
predisposed for eating only meat yeah we
have our ancestors have lived on the
subcontinent continent for about 70
75,000 years and we are adapted
naturally adapted to the kind of
vegetation and the kind of food sources
we have on the subcontinent so I don't
think the carnivore diet is the right
diet for Indians but if you want to try
it out entirely your choice who's
stopping
you
okay A7 blade says sir take my question
well I don't see a question I said that
what's your question I don't see it you
should have put the question
there
uh the just says is manusmriti casted
first of all I haven't read the manusi
and I don't think it's casted you know
this this term cast has been used to is
used as a stick to beat India with every
society has a hierarchial structure
every society has organization and
division of labor even mice like I said
some time ago they have structured
societies every without structure there
is no functioning Society without
hierarchy there is no functioning
Society look at Apple look at Microsoft
Microsoft look at any functional
Corporation there's a hierarchy and a
command structure look at the Armed
Forces look at any functioning
organization there is hierarchy and
there is division of labor and there is
a command structure and similarly with
any society you're going to have it but
in the case of India to demonize India
they have said this is cast system and
it is evil and there was no social
mobility and all that blah blah blah
blah blah so I am I'm just sick and
tired of this this this this crap
absolute utter
nonsense but yeah it's a it's a good
question thees I appreciate the question
but I don't I think it's castest I I
totally disagree with this nonsense now
mavin says recently a Pakistani woman
had a heart transplant in India as
pakistanis don't donate organs why do we
prioritize anyin naations of our own
people who are we trying to please I
it's a great question Mr mavin a
Pakistani girl woman whatever she came
to India she was poor she did not have
resources somebody brought her into
India and someone gave her someone
transplanted an Indian heart into her
and she's gone back to Pakistan she is
going to live a life there are lots of
Indians who need Hearts there are lots
of Indians who need various transplanted
organs kidneys and livers and spleens
and eyes and whatnot and there's a
shortage of these organs and you give a
heart to a Pakistani what on Earth is
this
nonsense I I I I just don't understand
what this is it's an enation they're not
our people they used to be they no
longer are our people they're not our
friends they they our enemies they wish
us
dead and we are giving extremely
precious and extremely scarse resources
to them what is this this is utter
Madness the organization that did this
needs to be investigated I hope the
government is doing
that all right I guess we are at the end
of today's episode once again two hours
almost 13 minutes so uh so yeah um this
is it uh we we end today's session over
here next week again I'm going to do
three sessions so I look forward to
seeing you all in at that time the first
one will be either on Tuesday or
Wednesday I'll put out I'll put on a
notification and it's going to be a live
chat session the next one okay so I look
forward to seeing you all there until
then thank you so much for all your
questions apologies to those of you
whose questions I could not take but I'm
going to do more of these live streams
so you will have more chances to
hopefully have me answer your questions
please ask your best questions I'll pick
as many of them as I can so until then
take care thank you so much for watching
and don't forget to keep raising your
standards every single day thank you so
much see you next time